<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Geospatial on Erin Austin</title>
    <link>https://ostens.github.io/categories/geospatial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Geospatial on Erin Austin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 18:15:53 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ostens.github.io/categories/geospatial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Command Line Reprojection</title>
      <link>https://ostens.github.io/command-line-reprojection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 18:15:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ostens.github.io/command-line-reprojection/</guid>
      <description>A lot of the data manipulation I do is FME-based these days for ease of use, but for reprojecting rasters the gdal toolset is just superior to any other tool because it requires no foreknowledge of the original projection of the dataset.
In many cases I&amp;rsquo;ll have a set of rasters which are all in slightly different projections (with different scaling latitudes, for example), so being able to reproject each raster on-the-fly is really useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cropping Rasters Using a Shapefile</title>
      <link>https://ostens.github.io/cropping-rasters-using-a-shapefile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 20:13:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ostens.github.io/cropping-rasters-using-a-shapefile/</guid>
      <description>At work I&amp;rsquo;m regularly delivered a batch of third-party geotiffs. They arrive in a localised projection and need to be converted into EPSG3857. Most annoyingly, some of the third-party providers don&amp;rsquo;t provide inset plans separately, so each time we&amp;rsquo;re sent updates, the inset plans need to cropped from the main charts and georeferenced.
To attempt to automate the process, I set up shapefiles for each inset plan, with a &amp;ldquo;chart&amp;rdquo; attribute corresponding to the main chart they would be derived from, and a &amp;ldquo;plan&amp;rdquo; attribute which they would eventually be named.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>